<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title/><link>https://raleighwi.se/</link><description>Recent content on</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 25 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://raleighwi.se/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Newsletter issue</title><link>https://raleighwi.se/newsletters/newsletter0/</link><pubDate>Fri, 25 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://raleighwi.se/newsletters/newsletter0/</guid><description>3 things I’ve found interesting Windows 11 just came out! Frosted glass is nice and Linux doesn&amp;rsquo;t exist apparently
Outer Wilds' loading times could be better, maybe if they implemented direct storage?
TVs are pretty hard to set up.
2 things I’ve been wondering about How to make tech more accessible for neurodivergent people
How bias in the STEM fields leads to less LGBTQ people joining tech.</description></item><item><title>Building a Next.js + Airtable singlelink clone.</title><link>https://raleighwi.se/posts/building-a-next.js-airtable-singlelink-clone/</link><pubDate>Sat, 15 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://raleighwi.se/posts/building-a-next.js-airtable-singlelink-clone/</guid><description>Singlelink cloned Backstory Recently, something fun happened! I got my first real commission of a website, and it just so happened that I had basically written it earlier that day. I had been building a site for a hackathon I might run at some point, and I wanted to be able to have it not be hard-coded and be more user-friendly than mdx.
I had recently learned about Airtable thanks to Hackclub, so I thought why not use this?</description></item><item><title>Forestry, a git-based CMS</title><link>https://raleighwi.se/posts/forestry-a-git-based-cms/</link><pubDate>Fri, 14 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://raleighwi.se/posts/forestry-a-git-based-cms/</guid><description>So as those who have been following me may know, I keep just upgrading my blog while not really writing for it. The problem with writing for this blog is that, as much as I love VSCode, it&amp;rsquo;s not the most effective for blog post writing. So I have been shopping around for a CMS that&amp;rsquo;ll work with my existing blog because I do not want to migrate my blog again.</description></item><item><title>Super16, a silly ISA</title><link>https://raleighwi.se/posts/super16/</link><pubDate>Thu, 13 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://raleighwi.se/posts/super16/</guid><description>Super16&amp;hellip; What is it? Super16 is my custom architecture for a theoretical CPU. It&amp;rsquo;s on github! I have designed the thing from the ground up, so here&amp;rsquo;s an overview:
Features: Text-out support 7 16-bit registers Binary compilation 16-bit data on every instruction Built-in screen drawing (pixel by pixel) Missing stuff: Any support for memory, I mean who needs that? Basic design: One instruction is composed of 32 bits, making up 3 catagories; Opcode, Register and data.</description></item><item><title>XKCD Explainer Button</title><link>https://raleighwi.se/posts/xkcd-button/</link><pubDate>Fri, 23 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://raleighwi.se/posts/xkcd-button/</guid><description>This project was just a little side-thing to learn how extensions.
So how do extensions work? Extensions are basically just a little website that runs when you open a compatible page. I have mine set up to run xkcd.js when xkcd.com is open. This is a really simple script so I&amp;rsquo;ll talk y&amp;rsquo;all through it. The full code is on github.
The code 1 var navbar = document.getElementsByClassName(&amp;#34;comicNav&amp;#34;)[0]; This line is pretty cool, thanks Randall for making the navbar have it&amp;rsquo;s own class name.</description></item><item><title>Stylegan2, Machine Minds, &amp; Science Communication</title><link>https://raleighwi.se/posts/stylegan-machine-minds-and-scicoms/</link><pubDate>Fri, 16 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://raleighwi.se/posts/stylegan-machine-minds-and-scicoms/</guid><description>AI is becoming a more and more important topic in our daily lives, and understanding has stayed about the same. I&amp;rsquo;m here to fix that! One of the very interesting new types of AI are GANs. For this article I&amp;rsquo;ll be talking about one Stylegan2. Stylegan2 is a huge leap in image generation GANs. I know I am a bit behind on this whole shebang, but I just found out that I could run Stylegan2 myself, so I wanted to write about it!</description></item><item><title>Domain name, finally</title><link>https://raleighwi.se/posts/domain-name-finaly/</link><pubDate>Wed, 14 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://raleighwi.se/posts/domain-name-finaly/</guid><description>So, I finally got l3gacy.tk linked to the github pages! The process was a bit confusing, probably because I&amp;rsquo;ve never done something like this before, but here&amp;rsquo;s the steps I took.
First I got a free domain from freenom.com. Quick tip, if you want one, write out the full domain in the domain search bar instead of just the first part (i.e. example.tk instead of just example). Once I had done that, I signed up for a free cloudflare acount, as they have a better domain-name-manegment-system-thing.</description></item><item><title>Got this working on github pages!</title><link>https://raleighwi.se/posts/got-this-working-on-github-pages/</link><pubDate>Tue, 13 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://raleighwi.se/posts/got-this-working-on-github-pages/</guid><description>Well, this was a pain in the butt.
I didn&amp;rsquo;t feel like messing with github actions again, as I hate that thing with a passion. So I was looking through the hexo docs and I found a usefull one-command deploy option. All you have to do is add this little tidbit to your _config.yaml.
1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9 10 11 deploy: type: git repo: https://github.</description></item><item><title>ethereum &amp; marshy, a new project!</title><link>https://raleighwi.se/posts/ethereummarshyanewproject/</link><pubDate>Sat, 13 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://raleighwi.se/posts/ethereummarshyanewproject/</guid><description>So a while back I was asked by my dad, &amp;ldquo;What does BitCoin have to do with these computer parts shortages?&amp;quot; Well I knew the basics of the blockchain idea, but I didn't know the specifics. So after a bit of googling I found out and that was that. Now a few days later I saw a video in my YouTube recommended feed: &amp;ldquo;Programming the blockchain with Ethereum!&amp;rdquo; or something like that.</description></item><item><title>Images made by writing bots?</title><link>https://raleighwi.se/posts/imagesmadebywritingbots/</link><pubDate>Thu, 18 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://raleighwi.se/posts/imagesmadebywritingbots/</guid><description>~Soo~ today we have something a tad bit more complicated, so first I'll introduce a few concepts and tools:
1\. Markov chains: From simple.wikipedia.org: &amp;ldquo;A Markov chain is a model of some random process that happens over time. Markov chains are called that because they follow a rule called the Markov property. The Markov property says that whatever happens next in a process only depends on how it is right now (the state).</description></item><item><title>better search for windows</title><link>https://raleighwi.se/posts/bettersearchforwindows/</link><pubDate>Wed, 20 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://raleighwi.se/posts/bettersearchforwindows/</guid><description>The Windows 10 search is slow and resource intensive. So I decided to build a new one!
The new search engine uses a flask-sqlite backend, using a jinja html front end.
It first indexes both of the drives and parses their files into the databases in a custom format
Then the front-end does a SQL query on the database to find the files. After that the custom jinja templates do a HTML &amp;ldquo;render&amp;rdquo; with the data from the query and send it to you!</description></item><item><title>mac OS X .... in a VM‽</title><link>https://raleighwi.se/posts/macosxinavm/</link><pubDate>Tue, 22 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://raleighwi.se/posts/macosxinavm/</guid><description>You may be thinking &amp;ldquo;Why is OS X so intresting?&amp;rdquo; Well this is intresting because it's running by a VM!
Firstly, you may be asking yourselves &amp;ldquo;Why would you do this?&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;What is the point of this?&amp;rdquo;.
The point is, I can, so why not‽
Moving on, how?
First, I installed the &amp;ldquo;Update to Catalina&amp;rdquo; app on my dad's MacBook Pro. I then followed a guide to transform this app into an .</description></item><item><title>Beach</title><link>https://raleighwi.se/posts/beach/</link><pubDate>Mon, 20 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://raleighwi.se/posts/beach/</guid><description>First blender project! First render: The idea for this was a volleyball scene on a beach island.
This was rendered in TV PAL 16:9.
Click to view
DO THIS FOR OTHER VIDEOS
Second render: Textures were reset for this one so I could fix the animation on this.
This was rendered in TV PAL 16:9.
Final render: What I changed here was I added textures to everything,</description></item><item><title>motion tracking</title><link>https://raleighwi.se/posts/motiontracking/</link><pubDate>Wed, 24 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://raleighwi.se/posts/motiontracking/</guid><description>I tracked approx 20 points in the image.
I extrapolated the movement of the camera.
I modeled the window and added the macbook and the drawers.
Then I exported to a set of 360 images and recombined them into a video.
That&amp;rsquo;s my youtube channel, btw</description></item><item><title>Rigging, not the election</title><link>https://raleighwi.se/posts/riggingnottheelection/</link><pubDate>Wed, 17 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://raleighwi.se/posts/riggingnottheelection/</guid><description>V1.0 Walk cycle animation done based on traditonal walk cycle animation.</description></item><item><title>Threadripper ad</title><link>https://raleighwi.se/posts/threadripperad/</link><pubDate>Tue, 21 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://raleighwi.se/posts/threadripperad/</guid><description> First I modeled the Treadripper CPU from AMD.
Then, I used rigidbody physics to simulate them bouncing away.
I used Windows Video Editor to sync the audio of the music I stiched together to the AMD text.
Finally I used Shotcut to edit all videos together.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://raleighwi.se/ramblings/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://raleighwi.se/ramblings/</guid><description>Welcome to my random thoughts! These views are my own and are not those of my employer or educator. Pls don&amp;rsquo;t sue them and get me fired. Here are some links!
Books: My reading list and maybe some thoughts on books Thoughts: A bunch of notes and/or research on random topics</description></item><item><title/><link>https://raleighwi.se/thoughts/books/brainfacts/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://raleighwi.se/thoughts/books/brainfacts/</guid><description>BrainFacts, a primer on the brain and nervous system This will mostly be just notes at first, and maybe some reflection later
Basics I already knew this, but we don&amp;rsquo;t just use 10% of our brains! Fun facts. 1 in 4 people suffer a neurological or psychiatric condition.
There are 2 types of neurons, some excite others and try to make them fire, and some inhibit others from passing signals. The latter can be useful for separating different circuits and columns from crosstalk when that is bad.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://raleighwi.se/thoughts/hisean/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://raleighwi.se/thoughts/hisean/</guid><description>Sean hi.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://raleighwi.se/thoughts/keyboards/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://raleighwi.se/thoughts/keyboards/</guid><description>Buying a keyboard Switches Based on my current research, tactile switches are the best bet for the most common type of typing I do. They provide nice feedback for typing when you aren&amp;rsquo;t looking, yet they wont be annoying for my family while I&amp;rsquo;m programming with them in the room. The most popular tactile switches are the Cherry MX Browns.
Form factor Based on some preliminary research, and a day of observing what I do on a keyboard, I have decided that a 65% keyboard would be best for me, as I need the arrow keys, but I do not use my numpad, except in certain edge-cases, in which cases I could just use my built-in numpad.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://raleighwi.se/thoughts/psychologyneuroscience/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://raleighwi.se/thoughts/psychologyneuroscience/</guid><description>Psychology and Neuroscience resources MIT OpenCourseWare Intro to Psychology Brain Facts Book this is the book I&amp;rsquo;m reading now. MCAT Psych Disorders</description></item><item><title/><link>https://raleighwi.se/thoughts/thoughts/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://raleighwi.se/thoughts/thoughts/</guid><description>Thoughts These are random thoughts and/or notes on basically anything.
Thoughts on the book I&amp;rsquo;m reading right now: Brain Facts Book, by brainfacts.org
What I&amp;rsquo;m learning: Psychology and neuroscience is my special interest right now!
Some links: Keyboards, or me trying to convince myself to spend $100 on a bunch of buttons Politics, a bunch of politics thoughts on government ability, and projects. Book List, my books that I have been reading.</description></item><item><title>Book List</title><link>https://raleighwi.se/books/list/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://raleighwi.se/books/list/</guid><description>Books, a cool thing This is a list of books I have read, am reading, or want to read, both fiction and not. My notes on some of these books will be linked next to them as I fill this out. Sadly this list is not exhaustive, but it may be at some point.
To Read Pirate Cinema by Cory Doctorow How Google Works by Eric Schmidt and Jonathan Rosenberg Current Snow Crash by Neal Stephenson Past 2021 Version Zero by David Yoon Project Hail Mary by Andy Weir BrainFacts Book, a primer on the brain and nervous system by BrainFacts.</description></item><item><title>Politics</title><link>https://raleighwi.se/thoughts/politics/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://raleighwi.se/thoughts/politics/</guid><description>Politics Cool stuff governments can do: Black budget projects these are things that allow the government to hide money from public expenses.</description></item></channel></rss>