<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Thoughts on</title><link>https://raleighwi.se/thoughts/</link><description>Recent content in Thoughts on</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://raleighwi.se/thoughts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title/><link>https://raleighwi.se/thoughts/books/brainfacts/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://raleighwi.se/thoughts/books/brainfacts/</guid><description>BrainFacts, a primer on the brain and nervous system This will mostly be just notes at first, and maybe some reflection later
Basics I already knew this, but we don&amp;rsquo;t just use 10% of our brains! Fun facts. 1 in 4 people suffer a neurological or psychiatric condition.
There are 2 types of neurons, some excite others and try to make them fire, and some inhibit others from passing signals. The latter can be useful for separating different circuits and columns from crosstalk when that is bad.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://raleighwi.se/thoughts/hisean/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://raleighwi.se/thoughts/hisean/</guid><description>Sean hi.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://raleighwi.se/thoughts/keyboards/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://raleighwi.se/thoughts/keyboards/</guid><description>Buying a keyboard Switches Based on my current research, tactile switches are the best bet for the most common type of typing I do. They provide nice feedback for typing when you aren&amp;rsquo;t looking, yet they wont be annoying for my family while I&amp;rsquo;m programming with them in the room. The most popular tactile switches are the Cherry MX Browns.
Form factor Based on some preliminary research, and a day of observing what I do on a keyboard, I have decided that a 65% keyboard would be best for me, as I need the arrow keys, but I do not use my numpad, except in certain edge-cases, in which cases I could just use my built-in numpad.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://raleighwi.se/thoughts/psychologyneuroscience/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://raleighwi.se/thoughts/psychologyneuroscience/</guid><description>Psychology and Neuroscience resources MIT OpenCourseWare Intro to Psychology Brain Facts Book this is the book I&amp;rsquo;m reading now. MCAT Psych Disorders</description></item><item><title/><link>https://raleighwi.se/thoughts/thoughts/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://raleighwi.se/thoughts/thoughts/</guid><description>Thoughts These are random thoughts and/or notes on basically anything.
Thoughts on the book I&amp;rsquo;m reading right now: Brain Facts Book, by brainfacts.org
What I&amp;rsquo;m learning: Psychology and neuroscience is my special interest right now!
Some links: Keyboards, or me trying to convince myself to spend $100 on a bunch of buttons Politics, a bunch of politics thoughts on government ability, and projects. Book List, my books that I have been reading.</description></item><item><title>Politics</title><link>https://raleighwi.se/thoughts/politics/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://raleighwi.se/thoughts/politics/</guid><description>Politics Cool stuff governments can do: Black budget projects these are things that allow the government to hide money from public expenses.</description></item></channel></rss>